<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-02-25T01:39:46-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog//</id><title type="html">Zihao’s Blog</title><entry><title type="html">Sixth week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/24/sixthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sixth week of classes" /><published>2017-02-24T03:02:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-02-24T03:02:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/24/sixthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/24/sixthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week was filled with pain and agony as I struggled through my first midterm and the competitive programming competition on Friday. Having been out of the testing psyche since last semester, this first test was something I was quite concerned about. I spent the majority of time trying to memorize the formulas I’ll be needing but I still felt defeated after the exam. In addition, I learned about quantum teleportation. So hopefully one day I’ll be able to teleport myself into another world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun thing that did happen was that my roommates and I almost burned down our apartment from a cooking accident. Despite that, the food turned out great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet again, a weekend of quantum information homework fun! Furthermore, I am trying to wrap up some school projects before I head to Montreal for spring break so it looks like I’ll be a busy beaver for the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects, projects, studying for this class! Over the next few weeks I’ll have 3 mid terms lined up right after another so majority of the week will be spent on studying and working through my school assignments. However, I do plan on to start learning how to bake various types of breads as a side hobby! Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class is definitely getting more challenging as I have to keep track of more Python syntaxes. But I do feel that the things we learn are very relevant and helpful in trying to appreciate what Python ahs to offer. In addition, I’m looking forward to the group project and see what my team and I will be able to accomplish and present at the end!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;
Check out these cool reads!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/24/how-to-secure-your-data-after-the-cloudflare-leak/&quot; title=&quot;Leaky Security&quot;&gt;Leaky Security!!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/24/super-smash-borg-melee-ai-takes-on-top-players-of-the-classic-nintendo-fighting-game/&quot; title=&quot;Robot's rise&quot;&gt;Robot’s rise!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fifth week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/15/fifthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fifth week of classes" /><published>2017-02-15T03:02:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-02-15T03:02:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/15/fifthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/15/fifthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was spent mostly on finishing Netflix for this class and working on quantum homework for my other class. Netflix took a while because there were many requirements that we needed to fulfill. In addition, it took us a while to come up with a way to get the RMSE under 0.95. Other than that, it’s been a pretty mundane week. I wish I had gone to career fair but due to classes I couldnt’t. In addition, Valentine’s day was pretty average too, nothing spectucular. Other than that, I had friends over for some nights and we just hung out and ate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantum homework. The bane of my semester. Don’t get me wrong, it is a great class but does require a lot of work if physics does not come intuitively. Other than that, I need to finish my Scientific computation homework and study for the test that I’ll be taking next Thursday. Then there are just a bunch of little assignments I need to fulfill such as my python homework and readings for this class. There are many small hurdles but I think I will be able to handle them and enjoy my weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I plan on attending the competitive programming competition on Friday and then go over to a friend’s house over the weekend. I don’t think anything interesting will happen, but I’m excited to take on the week as we inch closer to spring break. I also plan on studying a lot for my math test and hopefully do well on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Netflix project looked very easy in the beginning but towards the end I realized we had made a mistake in allowing ratings between 0 and 1 so we had to do some last minute changes and resulted in submitting the assignment late. The projects often have many details in them so it’s easy to miss a thing here and there. Overall, I really enjoy the class. We’re diving into Python deeper and deeper and sometimes I have to spend time outside of class to make sure I understand the various features Python has to offer and how certain methods act the way they do. I’m looking forward to the group projects!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atom editor! If you’re not a Vim or Emac wiz and you’re too poor to afford Sublime, you should try Atom! Atom editor has a lot of features installed and you have the opportunity to download a lot of plug-ins such as auto complete to make your life easier as a programmer. It’s versatile in that you can program in many different languages and it has a strong community supported by many.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fourth week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/09/fourthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fourth week of classes" /><published>2017-02-09T03:02:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-02-09T03:02:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/09/fourthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/09/fourthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I struggled through another week of quantum information. Originally I thought my semester would be easy, but looks like now it’s going to be one heck of a fight till the summer. This past week, most of what I did involved homework. My roommates and I started cooking more and we expanded our varieties to include baking and new recipes. In addition, after my roommate brought his Wii, I wasted many nights toying with that. Lastly, I attended a programming competition today. While I didn’t place in the top 3, I thought I greatly improved since last semester and it has motivated me to code more to get better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, quantum homework is in my way. I think the class is very interesting but the homework is difficult, at least for me. Besides that, I have several projects for classes such as this one and my security one that I need to do by next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I am going to continue trucking on through my classes and I’ll also be going to Houston to visit my mom for the weekend to celebrate her birthday. Nothing grand is planned but I do have a music concert tomorrow which I’m pretty excited about!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class is still going well for me. We are going more in depth into the syntax of python which I think is very good. I never knew all the nuiances that python had in terms of how it was built and how the variables interact with each other. Netflix project seems fun! It’s a bit confusing how it will be tested but if our assumptions are correct then I think we should be fine for the project. I’m curious what the class has in stored whether it’ll be more syntax regarding python or something else. The readings for the class are a lot and sometimes I get a bit confused about the material over javascript. Besides that, I’m enjoying it greatly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;keep.google.com! It’s a simple add on of Google that my roommate recommended to keep track of the list of things you have to do. It has a very easy interface and it can remind you also. The ease of it makes it appealing for people who don’t want to write things down each time. I have used it to keep track of the homework I need to do and the groceries I need to buy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Third week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/02/thirdweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Third week of classes" /><published>2017-02-02T12:33:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-02-02T12:33:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/02/thirdweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/02/thirdweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week things finally started to pick up for my classes. A lot of my activities centered around school. I thought taking 13 hours would be easy but it looks like it’s going to be a rough semester with the amount of work I’ll have to do for each class. Besides that, my roommates and I finally got our Wii working so we’ve spent several nights just goofing around and playing games. Furthermore, we watched Shutter Island, which we all agreed was a video mind twisting movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I need to finish my quantum homework. I need to also refresh my linear algebra skills for it too. In addition, I have to learn how to do synchronization for Java so I can do my homework for my intro to security class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I think my roommates and I will do a Bollywood night. In addition to drudging through my work load, I might start doing more readings so I can acquaint myself more with the world around me. And I think next Saturday, I will be attending a music concert which I’m greatly excited about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collatz is over! The class is still going very well. Some of the quizzes are becoming more challenging but I think the materials we cover are very relevant to what a work place would be like. Workflow was a pain in the butt for the first assignment but I thought the entirety of was still useful in providing us a guide. I really appreciate the fast Piazza responses the instructors give and the good advices that they provide whenever an opportunity comes up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharelatex! I used to do almost all of my work by writing it on a piece of paper. But with more math classes, I’ve learned to use Latex for the work. Instead of installing all the packages, you can easily use Latex through a website called Sharelatex. It allows easy and fast modifications along with providing auto complete and suggestions for what you type.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Second week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/26/secondweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Second week of classes" /><published>2017-01-26T12:33:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-01-26T12:33:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/26/secondweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/26/secondweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week I was assigned project 1 for this class along with homework for my quantum information class. I finished project 1 and I’m currenctly struggling through quantum information. I realized how terrible I am in linear algebra but I’m lucky that I have roommates who are willing to help me. Besides that, school has been fine. Wednesday night, my friends and I went out for dinner to send away one of our friends to Europe. And soon, I will be doing some tedious driving back and forth to celebrate Chinese New Year with my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I just have my quantum homework in my way. Besides that, I need to do a lot of reading for my math classes so I don’t fall behind. Trying to juggle school and fun will be a challenge this semester. In addition, I’m trying to be more healthy and hope to have time to exercise this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I will have to finish my homework and drudge through another week in my classes. It’ll basically be a lot of reading and learning outside of class and occasionally go out with friends to enjoy the semester. I hope to go on an adventure next week and explore nature and do something different than I have done before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working on project 1, I’m beginning to love the class more and more. The entire work flow felt like an actual software development experience and I am glad that I could learn the tools needed. I feel like this class will greatly prepare me for the real world and I can’t wait to see what’s in stored for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After struggling through my math classes, I discovered the wonderful tool called Mathematica. Mathematica is a math-centric programming language. It allows you to easily manipulate math and solve equations and provide visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/22/post1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First week of classes" /><published>2017-01-22T03:32:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-01-22T03:32:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/22/post1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/22/post1.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week was the beginning of the new semester. A lot of my time was spent on trying to figure out scheduling for my classes and trying to petition into the classes I wanted to. Unfortunately, after hours of constantly refreshing my waitlist page and the course schedule, I wasn’t able to get into some of the honor classes I hoped to. Like a good student, I attended all my classes and I think this will be a good semester. Everything I’m learning seems to be very interesting and I’m excited to see what I will be able to pick up in my quantum mechanics class. Other than school, my roommates and I watched a lot of TV and went and explored various parts of North Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to frantically see if I can do a late-add for a CS class I want to take. I should probably reorganize my desk and have a calendar that tracks my daily work and plan my weeks out ahead. There’s some homework that was assigned for 2 of my classes so I should probably get on those to make sure I’m not behind in the beginning of the school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I will try to finalize my course schedule and slowly settle into the semester. Then on Friday, I will drive to San Antonio and then to Houston to spend the weekend celebrating Chinese New Year with my parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I find this class really engaging and insightful. It goes into so many tiny details of software engineering and helps describe a lot of tools that I think I will use in the future. While I have some experience with Python, I really enjoyed how we went over line by line of the syntax and some nuances of Python that I didn’t look into before. The fact that the class feels like a conversation helps me retain the information better and keeps me more focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Jekyll for your blogs! I discovered the power of Jekyll while creating this blog and realized how nice the static generator site came out. Jekyll seems to be very easy to use with minimum knowledge needed for the Ruby parts, high recommend anyone to read the documentation and try it on their own https://jekyllrb.com/.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/22/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2017-01-22T03:32:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-01-22T03:32:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/22/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/01/22/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;Anurag wuz here. You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Anurag wuz here. You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>
