<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-22T18:16:39-05:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog//</id><title type="html">Zihao’s Blog</title><entry><title type="html">Almost there</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/20/thirteenthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Almost there" /><published>2017-04-20T04:02:54-05:00</published><updated>2017-04-20T04:02:54-05:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/20/thirteenthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/20/thirteenthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week was a bit of a haze. I remember registering for my classes and I think i was rather successful at that. Furthermore, my team and I scrambled to finish phase 3 of this project. It wasn’t the easiest phase because we thought visualization was due on Thursday and so we spent a lot of time on that. Other than that, I did homework for my other classes and I attended Google Games with my friends this Saturday. It was 6 hours of coding and puzzles and by the end of it we were all pretty exhausted. Luckily for us, we managed to get first place in the competition after facing some tough oppoonents and all of us got a really cool Google Home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finishing up my homework for Quantum information and finishing up a project for my security class. Other than that, I think I should start studying for my two finals on the last week of school and prepping my luggage to leave for San Francisco for the summer. It’s been a pretty calm few weeks and I also probably have to get together with my group and figure out presentation and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Saturday I will embark on a meat trip to some good ol BBQ in Texas with some friends. Other than that, I imagine I would be doing what I just described above trying to square things away. Shouldn’t be too bad of a week but nonetheless it’ll be busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refactoring is pretty confusing. I guess the concept isn’t that bad but having to follow all the code in class gets pretty confusing the more design patterns that we learn. But I’m still learning so that’s good. However, I wish the rubric for our project would be more clear. Because my team and I thought visualization was due on Thursday and so did many other team. From the rubric online, we understood it that way and that resulted in us having to rush to get the project finished. Other than that, class is nice and I’m excited to see and do the presentation for our project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Google Home to manage your life! Techs such as Google Home or Amazon Echo can make it really easy for you to check for things like news and weather while you are focused on another task. Doing so will allow you to reduce the time you spent searching for certain facts and using that time wisely on other aspects of your life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Almost there</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/14/twelfthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Almost there" /><published>2017-04-14T04:02:54-05:00</published><updated>2017-04-14T04:02:54-05:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/14/twelfthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/14/twelfthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week I felt more inactive than most weeks. Frankly, I don’t even remember what I did for the most part. I know that I worked on Quantum homework and that my group and I spent a lot of time in the lab working on phase 3. A fun thing that I do remember doing was going to Salt Lick with one of my roommates. The restaurant offered more than we had expected. Not only was it a meat heaven, it is decorated and well tendered to. It had lots of flowers and trees surrounding it in addition to music playing by a band along with lots of people chatting and laughing. Other than that, I attended a concert on Monday night. Which is pretty crazy for a Monday night if you ask me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantum homework. This week the homework is mostly based off of quantum algorithms. This means that I have to use my forgotten knowledge from cs331 and apply what I learned to the homework. Other than that, my group and I just need to finalize our phase 3 next week. I think most of it is already done so we shouldn’t have much trouble with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Saturday is Google Games! My team and I are extremely excited for it. We have our nerdy name and geeky outfits planned out. Should be a fun Saturday filled with challenges and swag. Other than that, I have to register for my classes for next semester. So I’ll take a few hours on Monday to plan out my schedule and hope that I get into them without trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQL was a nice portion of the class. Now coming into refactoring and working on Java, it is a little bit slow and sometimes a bit confusing with all the terms thrown around here and there. The book for refactoring is also extremely dense so it’s difficult to follow along with the examples. Working on Phase 3 is pretty fun as we get to see our hard work come together to form this pretty good looking and accessible website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use an online course planner instead of hand writing out the classes you want to take along with their teams. There are plenty of planners out there and the one I use is Coursicle. It has a very nice interface and it is very easy to use. Only con it has is that it doesn’t show any available graduate classes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Math is fun</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/06/eleventhweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Math is fun" /><published>2017-04-06T04:02:54-05:00</published><updated>2017-04-06T04:02:54-05:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/06/eleventhweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/04/06/eleventhweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week I got obliterated on my math midterm. It is worse than it sounds because the professor walked in and told us it is an easy test and then the test demolished me. Other than that, I did pretty horribly on all the quizzes for this class probably from the lack of time to study. Besides that, I had to finish homework for math and start doing my quantum homework for my quantum computing class. We did cover interesting algorithms this week regarding Shor’s algorithm and Grover’s algorithm. Other than that, it was just a lot of studying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft puzzle challenge! Tomorrow I will be attending the Microsoft Puzzle challenge with my team. It’s an all day event in which teams from all over the country work together to solve puzzles. The puzzles are difficult so we don’t really have high hopes going into it. In addition, I must finish up my homework for my classes and proceed to organize what I have to do for the following weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I think my team and I for this class will start doing phase3 of the IDB project. In addition, I’m assuming that I will be assigned more quantum homework so I’ll have to do that. Maybe next weekend, I will drive around Austin and explore it if time permits. Maybe I will go rock climbing, that sounds pretty fun and good way to rid stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting but difficult. While I do appreciate talking about SQL in class, it does take a while to get used to all the different aspects of it. In addition, the readings for this class is pretty long and the refactoring book is rather dry to read. Phase2 went better than phase1 but I think phase 3 will be quite challenging. I really enjoyed how we were allowed to stop class before 11:50 so the groups can get together and talk about it. This allowed my group and I to communicate more in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://oeis.org/
This week i stumbled upon this nice website that allows you to find formulas that calculate a certain sequence of numbers. It provides a basic explaination along with other peculiar facts about the sequence of numbers provided. It also comes in different languages. It’s pretty fun tool to use if you enjoy sequences of numbers and finding what’s special about them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Never bet</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/31/tenthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Never bet " /><published>2017-03-31T04:02:54-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-31T04:02:54-05:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/31/tenthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/31/tenthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week I learned to never gamble/make any bets and I got demolished at the competitive programming competition. Other than that, I spent a lot of my time with my group working on IDB phase 2. Originally we thought it wouldn’t take us a long time because we already set up the database in phase I, it turned out that there was still a lot to do and a lot of design questions we had to formalize. In the end, after a week of work, we were able to work through most of the project and fixed the bugs that we encountered. In addition, I cooked one of the worst meals I’ve ever cooked in my life this past week. But at least now I know what the smell of bad/rotten chicken stock is for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This upcoming week will be somewhat tedious and fun. I have to study for my math test coming up next week and I also have to knock out 3 assignments for my classes that are due soon. Other things include finishing up this project and possibly reading more news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly it’ll be a week of homework and studying for my math test. Other than wrapping up my school projects and assignments, on Friday there’s a programming competition that I wish to attend with some of my friends and on Saturday there’s a microsoft puzzle challenge I wish to attend if my team gets in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No more python??? It seems like we have transitioned into learning more about database design and various ways to format data. I like it. Having never been taught these things in any other classes, taking the time to go through the material and design and general knowledge of database seem to be very helpful for me. Currently, the project is a bit annoying with a lot of small things to figure out and a lot of unseen bugs along the way. Other than that, class is going well and I enjoy it very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;
Check out these cool reads!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/31/crunch-report-spacex-successfully-re-launches-a-rocket/&quot; title=&quot;Space X's successful launching of rocket&quot;&gt;Space X’s success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/31/now-whos-the-rich/&quot; title=&quot;Robinhood's higher evaluation&quot;&gt;Cheap fast trades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/gallery/april-fools-2017-heres-the-best-and-worst-of-this-years-pranks/&quot; title=&quot;April fools pranks&quot;&gt;Have some good laughs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Overachieving</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/23/ninthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overachieving " /><published>2017-03-23T04:02:54-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-23T04:02:54-05:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/23/ninthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/23/ninthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was the week of CS373 group project. Having just gotten done with the break, we realized that we didn’t really make any great strides in our project during the break. Nor did we the week before that because of the exam. So having gotten back on Monday, we decided to meet and work on it. In the beginning, we didn’t really know how much we had to do but after taking a closer look at the project we realized that we were in for the ride of our life. So since that Monday until the Thursday nignt when the project was due, my team and I went absolutely crazy every single day trying to finish and understand the project. After countless hours and late nights, we managed to pull it off to the best of our ability and I think we were all pretty satisfied in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studying for my math test that will be coming up in a week and doing my quantum homework for next week. Also patiently waiting for phase 2 of the SWE project so we can get started earlier this phase and finish it. Other than that, I have to drive back to San Antonio with a friend so she can make it to her MCAT testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finishing up homework and studying mostly. Maybe even help out my Dad with finishing up our house in San Antonio so we can put it up for sale soon. Seems like it’ll be a pretty laid back week, hopefully I’ll have more time to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought the project description for phase I was very confusing and it took a long time for us to understand what was expected. Particularly there were some typos in the project that confused us and it wasn’t resolved until we spoke with a TA. Other than that, I think the class is going well. I’m happy that we’re getting into SQL soon. Since I’ve never taken any database class, I feel this will be a good opportunity for me to learn and familiarize myself with it so we can do the backend in an efficient way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;
Check out these cool reads!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/25/uber-grounds-entire-self-driving-fleet-as-it-probes-arizona-crash/&quot; title=&quot;Self driving car problem&quot;&gt;Uber’s future of self driving cars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[S8’s future](https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/25/samsung-galaxy-s8-3/ “S8’s future)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Ai goes wrong](https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/25/japanese-authorities-decry-ongoing-robot-failures-at-fukushima/ “Robot failure in Fukushima)&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Short vacation</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/11/eightweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Short vacation " /><published>2017-03-11T03:02:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-03-11T03:02:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/11/eightweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/11/eightweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week I had to take both my exams in intro to security and quantum information on Tuesday. I didn’t feel too prepared for these as I had to move one test earlier in order so I could fly out to Canada. Getting back the results for those tests, I wasn’t too pleased but such is life and I suppose I’ll just have to work harder next time on it. Besides the midterms and studying, I managed to be able to fly to Canada on Friday to enjoy a short personal stay there exploring Montreal. There, I ate lots of good food, experienced lots of the cold weather and overall really enjoyed my stay there. It was a lot of fun and I think it was worth it as a mental break from all the school things that have been happening. Then slowly, I transitioned into finishing up my homework for my classes and familiarizing myself with the project for this class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of homework. Despite it being spring break, there’s still a lot of work that needs to be done and that are due the week when I come back. For instance, my team and I will have to figure out our approach to our project for this class and get everything set up. In addition, I have homework in pretty much every one of my classes that I need to pace myself over the week to try and finish before the break is over. Sadly, it won’t really be much of a break but I hope I can make good use of my time to finish the things that will be due soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homework homework homework! And perhaps learning more about the various frameworks that our project will need like AWS, Flask and front end. It won’t be easy but I think I can do it. Then I have to learn various things for my scientific numerical analysis class and finish the homework that has been assigned. In addition, I have to learn more about Markov chains and finish my python homework. So overall, it’ll just be a grudgingly slow week of work that must be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun fun fun! As we get more into the project, I think I will be able to learn a lot about how the different frameworks work together and how a team in the real world works together to accomplish the various goals. Furthermore, I think we will be able to put the techniques that we’ve been reading in our assigned reading to work and be able to see our ideas come to life slowly. Learning more about the syntax of Python such as decorators is also fun as I had never been introduced to certain concepts in Python beyond simple scripts. I think the rest of the semester will be challenging but rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;
Check out these cool reads!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/12/austin-is-fine-without-uber-and-lyft-until-it-isnt/&quot; title=&quot;Missing Uber and Lyft&quot;&gt;RIP Uber and Lyft&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/12/cosmo-ceo-michel-morvan-talks-about-augmented-intelligence/&quot; title=&quot;Augmented Intelligence&quot;&gt;Augmented Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/11/crispr-pioneer-jennifer-doudna-shines-hope-on-the-future-of-genetic-modification-at-sxsw/&quot; title=&quot;CRISPR innovation&quot;&gt;Crazy Science with CRISPR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rough week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/03/seventhweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rough week of classes" /><published>2017-03-03T03:02:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-03-03T03:02:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/03/seventhweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/03/03/seventhweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week was one filled with exams, projects and occasionally a brief moment of relief. I received my test back from one of my math classes and I took the SWE test on Thursday. I was a bit disappointed by both exams but rather than lamenting over it, I decided to forgo it this time and continued trucking on my project for my intro to security class along with studying for two more exams coming up soon. Right now it’s crunch time. Due to the fact that I’ll be leaving for Canada for the beginning of spring break, I have to rush to finish all my homework that will be due near the weekends so I don’t have to wander around the airports cursing at the air as to why I can’t finish my projects and homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One fun thing that did result from last week was from some get togethers with friends. There we played video games and hide and sick. It was a good time to catch my breath and get myself acquainted with the pace of school work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two exams on Tuesday and a project due Friday and a quantum homework due on Sunday and possibly some other things I can’t think of right now. It’ll be a pretty rough week so this weekend will be dedicated to lots of caffeine and restless nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, another thing that is in my way is to figuring out how to earn back the money I lost to the stock market this past week. This one will take some luck and time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Study study study! Most of my week will be spent on studying for my two midterms coming up soon. Furthermore, I have to finish my steganography proejct for intro to security along with figuring out the quantum nature of GHZ game and understanding how it works. Perhaps Monday I’ll watch some TV with friends and take a little breather before my tests. Then on the weekends, I will be in the glorious Montreal enjoying a short but much needed vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class is getting a bit more exciting with our upcoming group project. However, the python syntax we’ve been learning has been a little hard to keep track of, such as the various ways of unpacking variables and all the optional arguments. The test itself was average I would say. I was a little displeased with myself on how I performed but I think I will just work harder next time to improve. All in all, I think the class is still very interesting and applicable to the real world so I’m very satisfied with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;
Check out these cool reads!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/03/weekly-roundup-snaps-soaring-public-debut-major-aws-outage/&quot; title=&quot;AWE scare and SNAP boom&quot;&gt;SNAPIPO&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/03/ubers-vp-of-product-and-growth-has-left-the-company/&quot; title=&quot;Rocky times for Uber&quot;&gt;Rockytimes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/03/03/woe-are-the-great-fish-of-cape-cod/&quot; title=&quot;Power of hacking&quot;&gt;Hackers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sixth week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/24/sixthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sixth week of classes" /><published>2017-02-24T03:02:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-02-24T03:02:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/24/sixthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/24/sixthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past week was filled with pain and agony as I struggled through my first midterm and the competitive programming competition on Friday. Having been out of the testing psyche since last semester, this first test was something I was quite concerned about. I spent the majority of time trying to memorize the formulas I’ll be needing but I still felt defeated after the exam. In addition, I learned about quantum teleportation. So hopefully one day I’ll be able to teleport myself into another world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun thing that did happen was that my roommates and I almost burned down our apartment from a cooking accident. Despite that, the food turned out great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet again, a weekend of quantum information homework fun! Furthermore, I am trying to wrap up some school projects before I head to Montreal for spring break so it looks like I’ll be a busy beaver for the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects, projects, studying for this class! Over the next few weeks I’ll have 3 mid terms lined up right after another so majority of the week will be spent on studying and working through my school assignments. However, I do plan on to start learning how to bake various types of breads as a side hobby! Stay tuned for more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class is definitely getting more challenging as I have to keep track of more Python syntaxes. But I do feel that the things we learn are very relevant and helpful in trying to appreciate what Python ahs to offer. In addition, I’m looking forward to the group project and see what my team and I will be able to accomplish and present at the end!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;
Check out these cool reads!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/24/how-to-secure-your-data-after-the-cloudflare-leak/&quot; title=&quot;Leaky Security&quot;&gt;Leaky Security!!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/24/super-smash-borg-melee-ai-takes-on-top-players-of-the-classic-nintendo-fighting-game/&quot; title=&quot;Robot's rise&quot;&gt;Robot’s rise!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fifth week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/15/fifthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fifth week of classes" /><published>2017-02-15T03:02:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-02-15T03:02:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/15/fifthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/15/fifthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week was spent mostly on finishing Netflix for this class and working on quantum homework for my other class. Netflix took a while because there were many requirements that we needed to fulfill. In addition, it took us a while to come up with a way to get the RMSE under 0.95. Other than that, it’s been a pretty mundane week. I wish I had gone to career fair but due to classes I couldnt’t. In addition, Valentine’s day was pretty average too, nothing spectucular. Other than that, I had friends over for some nights and we just hung out and ate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantum homework. The bane of my semester. Don’t get me wrong, it is a great class but does require a lot of work if physics does not come intuitively. Other than that, I need to finish my Scientific computation homework and study for the test that I’ll be taking next Thursday. Then there are just a bunch of little assignments I need to fulfill such as my python homework and readings for this class. There are many small hurdles but I think I will be able to handle them and enjoy my weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I plan on attending the competitive programming competition on Friday and then go over to a friend’s house over the weekend. I don’t think anything interesting will happen, but I’m excited to take on the week as we inch closer to spring break. I also plan on studying a lot for my math test and hopefully do well on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Netflix project looked very easy in the beginning but towards the end I realized we had made a mistake in allowing ratings between 0 and 1 so we had to do some last minute changes and resulted in submitting the assignment late. The projects often have many details in them so it’s easy to miss a thing here and there. Overall, I really enjoy the class. We’re diving into Python deeper and deeper and sometimes I have to spend time outside of class to make sure I understand the various features Python has to offer and how certain methods act the way they do. I’m looking forward to the group projects!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atom editor! If you’re not a Vim or Emac wiz and you’re too poor to afford Sublime, you should try Atom! Atom editor has a lot of features installed and you have the opportunity to download a lot of plug-ins such as auto complete to make your life easier as a programmer. It’s versatile in that you can program in many different languages and it has a strong community supported by many.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fourth week of classes</title><link href="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/09/fourthweek.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fourth week of classes" /><published>2017-02-09T03:02:54-06:00</published><updated>2017-02-09T03:02:54-06:00</updated><id>http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/09/fourthweek</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://zihaozhu.me/blog/jekyll/update/2017/02/09/fourthweek.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do this past week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I struggled through another week of quantum information. Originally I thought my semester would be easy, but looks like now it’s going to be one heck of a fight till the summer. This past week, most of what I did involved homework. My roommates and I started cooking more and we expanded our varieties to include baking and new recipes. In addition, after my roommate brought his Wii, I wasted many nights toying with that. Lastly, I attended a programming competition today. While I didn’t place in the top 3, I thought I greatly improved since last semester and it has motivated me to code more to get better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s in your way?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, quantum homework is in my way. I think the class is very interesting but the homework is difficult, at least for me. Besides that, I have several projects for classes such as this one and my security one that I need to do by next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will you do next week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I am going to continue trucking on through my classes and I’ll also be going to Houston to visit my mom for the weekend to celebrate her birthday. Nothing grand is planned but I do have a music concert tomorrow which I’m pretty excited about!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my experience of the class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class is still going well for me. We are going more in depth into the syntax of python which I think is very good. I never knew all the nuiances that python had in terms of how it was built and how the variables interact with each other. Netflix project seems fun! It’s a bit confusing how it will be tested but if our assumptions are correct then I think we should be fine for the project. I’m curious what the class has in stored whether it’ll be more syntax regarding python or something else. The readings for the class are a lot and sometimes I get a bit confused about the material over javascript. Besides that, I’m enjoying it greatly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s my pick-of-the-week or tip-of-the-week?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;keep.google.com! It’s a simple add on of Google that my roommate recommended to keep track of the list of things you have to do. It has a very easy interface and it can remind you also. The ease of it makes it appealing for people who don’t want to write things down each time. I have used it to keep track of the homework I need to do and the groceries I need to buy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">What did you do this past week?</summary></entry></feed>
